Bangalore, India 6003778984

Mousam Kalita

mousam.kalita.official@gmail.com <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Github</u>

Frontend Software Engineer with over 3.5 years of experience, including collaboration with Fortune 500 companies and international remote teams at Deloitte. Demonstrated success in a fast-paced product company working directly with the CTO. A B.Tech graduate from NIT Silchar, excelling at the intersection of art and code.

EMPLOYMENT

Frontend Software Engineer

Premagic

May 2022 - Present

- Engineered a range of premium features for a B2B SaaS product, leading to a remarkable 200% increase in year-over-year revenue. Major clients included Mercedes, Accel Partners, Samsung, Shell, Rashtrapati Bhavan, G20 Summit, Asia Berlin, Gitex Dubai, JS and React conference, Nasscom, SaaSBoomi, Legrand, Currency Research, Genpact, TEDx, Nas Summit, Schneider Electric, Confederation of Indian Industry, The Bench, IBPC, TDP party, celebrity weddings, etc.
- Developed the Al-powered networking module (Ripple) for event attendees, which proved to be twice as effective as traditional networking methods (e.g. business cards). It became the most popular feature, serving over 3,000 participants per event and achieving a 95% satisfaction rate.
- Introduced image compression for 30 million monthly uploads, using MozJPEG and Pica, leveraging Web Workers and WebAssembly. Achieved a 40% reduction in data size, leading to decreased server costs and improved latency.
- Redesigned sponsor-focused features for top brands like Adobe, Amazon, and Verizon, boosting visibility by 30%. Included AI gallery displays, sponsor categorization, clickable links, and watermarking.
- Implemented 4+ custom AI-driven Digital Asset Management features for Rashtrapati Bhawan, securing a 3-year contract after a successful demo with the CTO to their IT team. The app was inaugurated by the President of India.
- Spearheaded the implementation of 5+ custom features worth over \$350K for the TDP's political campaign, supporting 180K attendees, 300K images, 200K image downloads, and 190K social posts. This helped the TDP win 164 of 175 seats and played a key role in the formation of the 2024 government.
- Collaborated with the design team to develop a QR code poster system for 1,600+ monthly events, generating 192,000 posters across 15+ countries. Enabled customization, sponsor logos, MP3 voiceovers, and more.
- Revamped the AI Gallery, serving over 4 million images daily, by introducing design enhancements such as 50+ theme variations, 500+ font options, customizable text and colors, and advanced image color extraction.
- Increased user-generated content volume by 50%, resulting in over 290K social posts YoY, by introducing native app photo sharing and LinkedIn post previews featuring the top 3 images of attendees.
- Transformed the client's event landing pages by architecting a lightweight photo gallery widget using Preact and Turborepo, easily integrable into the website with just 10 lines of code, which displays the best images of the event.
- Conducted 30+ interviews, performed code reviews, resolved over 100 technical issues, and provided tech support.

Coding Bootcamp

Udemy/Prepbytes

September 2020 - April 2022

- Built 14+ projects and learned Frontend, Data structures, Algorithms, React.js, Javascript, Typescript, HTML, and CSS.
- Projects: Amazon E-commerce store (Live link | Github link), Image editor (Live link), Instagram (Live link)

IT Analyst (Software)

Deloitte

June 2019 – Aug 2020

- Contributed to improved client satisfaction, stakeholder management, and audit outcomes for clients like Starbucks, Nordstrom, Daktronics, Daikin, and more.
- Enhanced productivity and reduced report generation time by 3 hours through the automation of existing workflows using Python and Pandas, resulting in substantial time savings for the client.
- Spearheaded projects for Fortune 500 companies, impacting over 10 major clients. Conducted comprehensive scoping and risk assessments across 5+ controls and 4 IT systems, effectively mitigating risks of fraud and financial misstatements.
- Conducted rigorous testing on infrastructure controls, assessing operating systems such as Windows and Linux, as well as databases including Oracle DB and SQL DB.

EDUCATION

- National Institute of Technology, Silchar (B.Tech in Mechanical). Grade: 8.40/10 (Final semester SPI)
- Kendriya Vidyalaya. Class 12 Percentage: 95.6%. Class 10 Grade: 9.8/10

Languages and Technologies

React.js, Javascript (ES6), HTML, CSS, Typescript, Redux, Git, Webpack, Vite, Nx, Preact, Mixpanel, Sentry, SCSS, Responsive design, Next.js (familiar), CI/CD, Node.js (familiar), Python (familiar), Electron (familiar), C++ (familiar).